Michael Park

Seattle, WA | 206-720-6454 | thatmichaelpark@gmail.com

Profile

Software developer with a B.S. in computer science as well as experience in technical writing and interacting with customers. Comfortable with the following:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript - Electron

- jQuery - TDD with Mocha, Chai, and Supertest

Angular.js - OOP

React - Data structures and algorithms

Node.js - Pair programming

Express.js
PostgreSQL
- Git, Github

MongoDB - Johnny-Five

Bootstrap, Materialize.css and Material-UI - C, C++, C#

Education

Galvanize | Seattle WA | Certificate, Web Development

University of Washington | Seattle, WA | M.A., Music

University of Ottawa | Ottawa, Canada | B.S., Computer Science

Select Projects (see portfolio: thatmichaelpark.github.io)

Fractal Jigsaw Puzzle

- A jigsaw puzzle made of smaller jigsaw puzzles made of smaller jigsaw puzzles; built using HTML Canvas, JavaScript

Gadgetina

- A music keyboard/MIDI controller based on the Wicki-Hayden key layout; built using P8X32A microcontroller, custom printed circuit boards, custom enclosure

Sphinx

- Self-hosted compiler for the Parallax P8X32A Propeller microcontroller.
- Awarded 3rd place in the Propeller Design Contest 2009-2010

Experience

Full-Stack Web Developer

High Seas Consulting | Seattle, WA | 2016

Full-Stack Web Development Fellow

Galvanize | Seattle, WA | 2016

- Developed a jigsaw puzzle with moving edges. Built using React, Node, Express, PostgreSQL. Companion editor built with Angular and Electron.
- Developed a multi-user drum machine. This was a group project. We used React and Socket.io for the front end, Node, Express, and PostgreSQL for the back end. I was responsible for the drum machine operation and the chat functionality.
- Developed a family tree database with graphical front end. This was a group project. I wrote the family tree drawing routine. Node/Express/PostgreSQL back end serving EJS pages.
- Developed a sliding-tile puzzle using JQuery-UI drag-and-drop and the Flickr API.
- Developed a multi-player tank game with 3D wireframe graphics and analog controls. I wrote the graphics and networking code using HTML canvas and Socket.io.
- (All the above projects can be seen at <u>thatmichaelpark.github.io</u>.)

Owner/Manager

Renton Computers | Renton, WA | 2014 - 2016

- Owned and managed a computer repair store.
- Developed web-based point-of-sale and ticket-tracking software for in-store use.

Various | Seattle, WA | 2011 - 2013

- Served as Secretary on HOA. Regularly updated website with new content; improved communications with homeowners.
- Tutored math and computers as a volunteered at the Big-Brained Superheroes Club (after-school program).
- Spent a lot of time at a makerspace/hackerspace; worked on projects; ran meetups; tutored electronics and programming.

Technical Writer

CTL2 | Seattle, WA | 2010

- Wrote training material for a proprietary programming language, electronics testing, and car sales
- Created GUI for CTL2's e-learning system.

Programmer Writer

Microsoft | Redmond, WA | 1998 - 2009

- Created and maintained documentation and code samples for Visual C++ team.
- Developed a program to help convert C# code samples to Managed C++.